## Profile — Web developer

I'm a Computing Engineer with more than 7 years of professional computer engineer experience and strong skills in web development. I'm also a creative person, with extensive knowledge of graphic design, UX/XD, usability and SEO, who is open to new projects, learning and growing.

# **Professional Experience**

ThoughtWorks Inc February 2012 — Current

Web developer, involved in different projects and applying the following skills:

**Developer:** Test-driven development and Behaviour-driven development with Ruby and Sinatra framework, infrastructure as code (devops) using puppet and fabric, agile methodology, continuous delivery and one-click deployment using Go.

**UX**: graphic design, user experience, user testing, guerrilla testing and research, frontend development with CSS<sub>3</sub> and HTML<sub>5</sub> fully responsive websites.

#### Alquimia Proyectos Digitales March 2007 — January 2012

Leader of frontend team, developing SEO optimized, W<sub>3</sub>C valid HTML and CSS top quality themes, including projects with short deadlines, usability-oriented, cross-browser and legacy browser compliant, modifying and improving external themes or working as a team with other leading companies.

#### UNICEF España — http://www.unicef.es and http://tienda.unicef.es

Theming and Information Architecture design for corporative site and ecommerce shop, collaborating with a partner software development company, managing complex theming development including some custom code.

#### United Nations (UN) — http://www.sinexcusas2015.org

Rapid theming and development with legacy code from an external company, client communication and custom development.

## Spanish Official Vaccine Advisory Committee — http://www.vacunasaep.org Spanish Association of Pediatrics — http://www.aeped.es/

Graphic design from scratch, cross-browser themes, client communication and user experience.

## Webalquimia — http://al.quimia.net

Full multilanguage company website with mobile-first design, including visual graphicdesign from scratch, Information Architecture development, responsive HTML5 and CSS3 themes.

**Andalusian Regional Government** — Drupal course teacher for Instituto Andaluz de Administración Pública.

**More than 30 different projects** from Drupal 4.7 to Drupal 7 — Including frontend and backend development, content types definition and implementation, module development, ecommerce websites, customizing third-party themes.

Freelance webpages developer, modifying and creating from scratch some handmade websites and working with different CMS — Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal — from 2005 to 2007

**Humiservi Climatización y Control, S.A** — Main role of User Interface in a C++ SCADA system for house and industry automation project, developing a fully programmable GUI.

**Unión Grafijerez artes gráficas** — Two-month internship in a printing office, working as graphic designer and layout designer.

## **Education**

Computer Science BsC — Spanish pre-Bolognia equivalent, ITIG. University of Cadiz (Spain) — 2004/2011

**Highest grade** for **Final Year Thesis** — Multiplatform dominoes game developed with Python and using Expert Systems for its Artificial Intelligence, available at http://dominous.forja.rediris.es/

#### **Technical Skills**

**Programming languages** PHP, Python, C/C++, Ruby, Javascript

Web Frontend HTML5/CSS3 semantic, accessible and maintainable markup

**Database management** MySQL, Oracle

Graphic design Vector and bitmap software — Adobe and Corel suite

Control Version Systems SVN, GIT

Operating Systems GNU/Linux, Windows and Mac OSX

# Courses, congress and seminars

Kevin Werbach Gamification course with 94.65% completion grade — University of Pennsylvania

National an international congress and seminars attendance about Computing Science and web development

- BBC Developer Conference Big Data (SQL & NoSQL) 2012
- Drupal congress Drupalcamp Barcelona 2007, Drupalcamp Sevilla 2011
- Social network and blogging congress EBE 2009, 2011
- I, II, III, IV Free Libre Software conference of University of Cadiz. 2004, 2005, 2006 and 2009 years.
- I and II Open Source World Conference, 2004 and 2006. Palacio de Ferias y Congresos de Málaga.
- II New technologies seminar. Cadiz Council Diputación de Cádiz and REI, 2004.
- Intellectual Property, Free Libre Software and University 2006, Libre Software and Open Knowledge Office, University of Cadiz.
- Secure software development seminar. E-Business, Social Science and Communication Technologies and Jerez Business School. 2006.

## Additional information

- First Prize in atrÉBT! Entrepeneur University Contest.
- Paper author and workshop about "Editing digital audio with Audacity" in Free Libre Software conference of University of Cadiz. ISBN13: 978-84-9828-055-5
- Active collaboration in Xinug Computer Association, organizing activities, seminars and Lan Parties, working in:
  - Logistics and network deployment.
  - Visual branding design with posters, flyers, t-shirts and more.
  - Competition judge and graphic design contest organizer.
- Organizer and visual branding graphic designer for FLOSS Free/Libre/Open Source Systems International conference.
- Scientific paper translation for NovÁTIca (Spanish National Computer Science Journal)
- Cover and back design for "Eres Dulce" diabetes self-help book.

# Websites and portfolio

Personal website — http://www.3oheme.com